Guide to the Virginia Gardner Papers TAM.100
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Virginia Gardner Papers
1913-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Gardner, Virginia
TAM.100
10.25 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons, one manuscript box and one oversize box.
Virginia Gardner (1904-1992) was a journalist, Communist, and biographer of Louise Bryant. She worked at several midwestern newspapers before joining the Chicago Tribune in 1930. Around 1937, she joined the Communist Party and was fired from the Tribune for her union activism in 1940. She then went to work for the Women's Division of the Democratic National Committee in New York and was briefly Executive Secretary of the American Council on Soviet Relations in Washington D.C.. She was active in the Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges, and wrote for the Federated Press (a labor news service), The New Masses, Peoples World (the CPUSA West Coast newspaper) in Los Angeles and the Daily Worker in New York where she covered the Rosenberg case in 1953. Gardner wrote The Rosenberg Story in 1954 and Friend and Lover, a Louise Bryant biography in 1982. The collection includes her correspondence, documentation of her political activities, research materials, manuscripts, autobiographical materials, photographs, and articles.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by John Marberry, son of Virginia Gardner, in 1990. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1990.013 and 1990.014.
Historical/Biographical Note
Virginia Gardner (1904-1992) was a journalist, communist, and biographer of Louise Bryant. She was raised in Fort Smith, Arkansas and graduated with a B.A. in journalism from the University of Missouri in 1924. She worked at several Midwestern newspapers before joining the Chicago Tribune in 1930. Gardner gradually became a radical and joined the Communist Party around 1937. She led the small Newspaper Guild group at the Tribune and was fired for her union activism in March, 1940.
Blacklisted in Chicago, she moved to New York where she worked with the Women's Division of the Democratic National Committee. After her divorce from journalist Marion (Red) Marberry, Gardner moved to Washington, DC in 1942, and was briefly Executive Secretary of the American Council on Soviet Relations. Between 1940 and 1942 Virginia Gardner was active as a member of the Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges, serving as its Executive Secretary in 1941. From 1942-1943 she worked for the Federated Press (a labor news service), resigning over its unwillingness to criticize John L. Lewis. Gardner next worked for the New Masses, resigning in 1947 when it became a monthly.
She moved to Los Angeles, working for the Peoples World (the CPUSA West Coast newspaper) until her dismissal in 1951, and was then briefly employed at a meat packing plant. In 1952 Gardner moved to New York where, again, her first job was at a meat plant in Jamaica, Queens, before being employed by the Daily Worker where she covered the Rosenberg case in 1953, and later wrote The Rosenberg Story, which was published in 1954. In 1959 Virginia Gardner left the Worker, and between 1960 and 1962 worked as a medical writer. From 1963 to 1971 she worked as editorial assistant to Corliss Lamont. Her Louise Bryant biography was published in 1982. Soon afterwards she began working on her own autobiography. Gardner died in San Diego on January 5th, 1992.
Chronology
June 27, 1904: Born in Sallisaw, Oklahoma. Has two older sisters, Gertrude Miller and Katharine Carson.
1910: Mother dies when she was 10 years old.
1921 to 1924: Attended University of Missouri, graduated with a Bachelor of Journalism.
Dec. 17, 1927: Married Jerome Butler, a socialist newspaperman and copy reader
1927: Employed at the St. Louis Times.
May 1927: Father dies.
1929: Hired by Chicago Tribune.
July, 1937: Married Marion (Red) Marberry whom she described as a leftist who never joined the Party. He was also a newspaperman and wrote three books:Joaquin Miller American Poet (1953); Vicky: A Biography of Victoria Woodhull (1967); The Golden Voice: A Biography of Isaac Kelloch (1947).
September, 1937:"Decided to join the Communist Party."
April, 1938: Joined the Newspaper Guild in Chicago.
1938: Active in Hearst strike in California.
1939: Joined the Communist Party.
1939: Filed charges with the National Labor Relations Board regarding unfair treatment at Chicago Tribune.
1939: Assisted in publishing the Tribunit, a publication of the Chicago Tribune workers.
March 22, 1940: Dismissed from Chicago Tribune, because of involvement in Guild activities at the paper.
1940: Moved to New York where she worked with the Women's Division of the Democratic National Committee.
1941: Voted as lifetime member of the Newspaper Guild.
1941: Acted as Executive Secretary of the Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges (President of the ILWU),in New York City in an attempt to prevent his deportation from the United States.
1942: Moved to Washington D.C.; Divorced Marion (Red) Marberry (January); Begins work at Federated Press, a labor news service; serves as Executive Secretary to the American Council on Soviet Relations, a precursor to the National Council of American Soviet Friendship (NCASF).
1943: Resigned from Federated Press. Began working as Washington correspondent for New Masses.
1947: Resigned from New Masses, and moved to Los Angeles; where she began working for The Peoples World
1948: Subpoenaed to appear before the Tenney Committee (California's Fact-Finding Committee on Un-American Activities).
1949: Wrote a few articles for Masses and Mainstream.
1951: Dismissed from The Peoples World.
1952: Moved back to New York; employed in Jamaica, Queens in a meat packing plant.
1954: The Rosenberg Story, published by Masses and Mainstream.
1955: Began work at the Daily Worker.
December 1959: Resigned from the Worker.
Feb.-June 1960: Worked on staff of Factor, a monthly magazine which covers issues related to psychiatry.
1960 to 1962: Freelanced as a medical writer.
1962: Left the Communist Party.
1963 to 1971: Employed as editorial assistant to Corliss Lamont.
1982: Published Friend and Lover, a biography of Louise Bryant (New York:
1984 to 1989: Worked on her unpublished autobiography.
1989: Grandson, John Dorney dies; in failing health.
1992: Dies in San Diego, January 5th.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes Virginia Gardner's correspondence, documentation of her political activities, research materials, manuscripts, autobiographical materials, photographs, and articles.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series, as follows:
Series I: Autobiography, Series II: Correspondence, Series III: Political Activities, Series IV: Journalism Career, Series V: Correspondence Addendum, Series VI: Research Files, Series VII: Unprocessed Materials, Series VIII: Photographs
Folders are arranged either alphabetically or chronologically based on the nature of the series.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Typescripts.; Communists -- United States.; Articles.; Files (document groupings); Correspondence.; Autobiography (genre); Women journalists |z United States.; Newspaper columns.; Journalism, Communist -- United States.; Death certificates.; Collective bargaining |x Journalists |z Illinois |z Chicago.; Birth certificates.; Biography (genre); Single mothers |z United States.; Interviews.; United States |x Foreign relations |z Soviet Union.; Women communists -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); People's world (San Francisco, Calif.); American Council on Soviet Relations; Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges; Chicago Tribune (Firm); Masses & mainstream.; Bridges, Harry, 1901-; Bryant, Louise, 1885-1936; Allen, Bill, 1914-; Gardner, John.; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Tessitore, John.; Spector, Frank.; Sessions, Kay Hall.; Communist Party of the United States of America; Newspaper Guild; Hennacy, Ammon, 1893-1970; Hardesty, Corrine.; Richmond, Al, 1913-1987.; Unger, Nick; Williams, William Appleman; Bridges, Nikki; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953; McGrath, Thomas, 1916-1990.; Hilliard, Noel; Daily Worker (New York); Garlin, Sender
- Series I: Autobiography, 61247
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Autobiography contains a lengthy and rather personal unpublished untitled autobiographical typescript, related correspondence, and a genealogy and other biographical materials.
  - Subseries I:A: Personal data documents., 61285
    - Address Book, undated; 61294 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence seeking residency at Renwick Gardens., undated; 61293 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Genealogy, 1954-1984; 61292 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Insurance Book, 1952-1953; 61291 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Misc. personals., 1922-1985; 61290 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Personal Data, 1971-1973; 61289 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Photoprints, 1951-1983; 61288 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Photoprint copy of 50th Reunion of Fort Smith Class, undated; 61287 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wills, etc., 1968-1987; 61286 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I:B: Autobiography., 61257
    - A Summary, undated; 61284 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Chapter Plan, undated; 61283 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - John Tessitore's copy with his comments., undated; 61282 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 1 -Other Singular Lives, undated; 61281 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 2 -Life at Columbia Missouri., undated; 61280 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 3 -Saskatchewan., undated; 61279 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 4 -Pawhuska., undated; 61278 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 5 -From Fort Smith to Kansas City., undated; 61277 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 6 -Father., undated; 61276 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 7 -Depression., undated; 61275 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 8 -Dr. Gerty., undated; 61274 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 9 -Red and I Marry., undated; 61273 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 10 -Red Joins The Picketline., undated; 61272 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 11 -John is Born., undated; 61271 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 12 -A Stupid Business., undated; 61270 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 13 -I Got Sold Down The River., undated; 61269 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 14 -The Letter Bridges Pocketed., undated; 61268 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 15 -Father and Son., undated; 61267 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 16 -Back to Reporting., undated; 61266 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 17 -An Exciting Visitor., undated; 61265 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 18 -New Friends and Old., undated; 61264 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 19 -I Learn a Lesson, or 1 or 2., undated; 61263 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 20 -Criticism and SelfCriticism., undated; 61262 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 21 -Back to New York., undated; 61261 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 22 -Not the Best of Years., undated; 61260 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 23 -Julius and Ethel Rosenberg., undated; 61259 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 24 -Milt Again., undated; 61258 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Subseries I:C: Correspondence regarding Autobiography., 61248
    - Carrol, Joe, 1985-1986; 61256 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cohen, Hy (Publisher), 1988; 61255 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Gerty, Dr. (Psychiatrist), 1964-1987; 61254 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Pashe, Vic, 1985-1986; 61253 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Re: publication of autobiography, 1984-1989; 61252 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Richmond, Al, 1985; 61251 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Research notes, undated; 61250 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Stevens, Don, 1940-1985; 61249 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Series II: Correspondence, 61178
  Series II: Correspondence is divided into personal (family and friends) and political correspondence and spans the years 1922 to 1990. Personal correspondents include her son John Marberry, her nephew John Gardner, several friends, and boyfriends Brady Pryor, Dud Jarret, Paul Cawthron, Andy Anderson, John McShane, and Milt Rogart and his wife. The political correspondence is with communists, other radicals and several well-known writers, including Bill Allen, Sender A. Garlin, Ammon Hennacy, Corrine Hardesty, Corliss Lamont, Kay Hall Sessions, Frank Spector, John Tessitore, Nick Unger, Harry and Nikki Bridges and William Appleman Williams.
  - Subseries II:A: Correspondence with relatives., 61221
    - Carson, Katharine, 1933-1984; 61246 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Carson, Katharine - Newspaper article regarding her novel, 1939; 61245 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Dorney, John, 1989; 61244 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Dorney, John - death, 1989; 61243 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Gardner, Carolyn, 1970; 61242 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Gardner, Carolyn: Newspaper article re death of, undated; 61241 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1964-1965; 61240 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1970; 61239 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1976; 61238 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1977; 61237 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1978; 61236 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1979; 61235 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), undated; 61234 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1965; 61233 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Gardner, John (VG's nephew), 1980; 61232 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Marberry, John (VG's son), 1947-1984; 61231 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Marberry, John and family photoprints (photocopies of), 1976-1977; 61230 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Marberry, Red (Marion) - John's father, undated; 61229 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Marberry Relatives, 1939-1962; 61228 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Miller, Gertrude, 1929-1967; 61227 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Miller, Gertrude - burial of, 1969; 61226 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - G.R. Wood of the Above Ground Review, discusses John Gardner, 1973; 61225 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Misc. from relatives, 1930-1987; 61224 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Misc. notes and correspondence, 1984-1990; 61223 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Misc. notes and correspondence, 1930-1939; 61222 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II:B: Correspondence with close friends, 61208
    - Anderson, Brady, 1925-1930; 61220 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cawthron, Paul and Dud Jarret, 1923-1943; 61219 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Frank, 1970-1973; 61218 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Gauldin, Sara, 1982-1987; 61217 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gauldin, Sara - on the Manuscript of Louise Bryant, undated; 61216 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gauldin, Sara - Poetry, undated; 61215 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - McShane, John, 1935-1981; 61214 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Pryor, Brady, 1922-1943; 61213 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Rogart, Milt (see chapter 24 of autobiography), undated; 61212 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Rogart, Pat (Milt's wife), 1970-1971; 61211 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Sullivan, Nancy, 1984-1987; 61210 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - VG's copies of outgoing correspondence, 1946-1989; 61209 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Subseries II:C: Political correspondence, 61179
    - Abrowitz, Murray - M.D., 1964-1981; 61207 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Allen, Bill, 1944; 61206 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Coleman, Louis (Limey), 1974-1975; 61205 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Coover, Robert, 1977; 61204 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Garlin, Sender A., 1965-1983; 61203 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Garrigue, Jean - Poet, 1972-1973; 61202 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Grossner, Isabel, 1984-1988; 61201 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Hardesty, Corrine, 1983-1986; 61200 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Hennacy, Ammon, 1958-1969; 61199 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Hillard, Noel, 1954-1978; 61198 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Hillard, Noel, 1979-1985; 61197 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1985-1987; 61196 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1975-1978; 61195 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Lamont, Corliss - regarding his autobiography, 1969; 61194 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Lindsay, Vina, 1928-1929; 61193 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Marzani, Carl - Regarding trial of, undated; 61192 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - McGrath, Tom, 1956-1970; 61191 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Murray, George and Virginia, 1972-1989; 61190 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Harvey O'Conner, Harvey - obituary, undated; 61189 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Richmond, Al, 1981-1983; 61188 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Rosemary, 1967; 61187 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Segure, Rose, 1966-1973; 61186 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Sessions, Kay Hall, 1962-1985; 61185 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Spector, Frank, 1951-1985; 61184 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Stone, Jack and Bert Stone, (Jack edited On The WashingtonRecord, copy of volume I, June 27, 1965, is included, 1955-1970; 61183 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Tessitore, John A., 1981-1989; 61182 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Under, Nick, 1971; 61181 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Williams, William Appleman, 1966-1967; 61180 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Series III: Political Activities, 61151
  Series III: Political Activities, is divided into two sections: A. General, which contains files on the Rosenberg case, the American Council on Soviet Relations, and Gardner's testimony before various legislative committees; and B. The Harry Bridges Case, which contains clippings, correspondence between Gardner and Harry and Nikki Bridges, and Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges materials related to the campaign to prevent his deportation from the United States.
  - Subseries III:A: Political activities, 61164
    - VG's statement before Senate Judicial Committee regarding Francis Biddle's nomination as U.S. Attorney General., 1941; 61177 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - American Council on Soviet Relations, 1942; 61176 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - American Council on Soviet Relations, 1942; 61175 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - VG's annotated copy of Party Voice, V.II, #6, September to October 1954., undated; 61174 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - VG and the Tenney UnAmerican Committee, 1948; 61173 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Political Beefs, 1955-1976; 61172 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - News Release to Moscow Tass and Sovietskaya Kultura, regarding death of Fred Ellis., 1965; 61171 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - News release from, New York State Communist Party, State Committee, 1957; 61170 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Misc. apparently from Party Members, 1959-1970; 61169 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Related to publication in Catholic Digest of "Labority Within Cloistered Walls," 1961., 61168 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - National Committee to Reopen Rosenberg Case, 1988; 61167 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Unidentified, but related to a Congressional Committee Hearing, undated; 61166 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Misc., 1928-1990; 61165 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Subseries III:B: Harry Bridges Case., 61152
    - Findings and Conclusion of the Trial Examination in the Matter of Harry Bridges, a publication of the U.S. Government Printing Office, 1939; 61163 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Newspaper clippings and Brief by Lawyers Guild on Harry Bridges Case, 1941; 61162 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - ILWU Handbook in recognition of Harry Bridges, 1941; 61161 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Releases from Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges, 1941; 61160 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Newspaper clippings on Harry Bridges Case, 1941; 61159 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Newspaper clippings on Harry Bridges Case, 1941-1942; 61158 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Auditors Report on Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges and other correspondence related to his deportation, 1941-1942; 61157 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper articles on Harry Bridges Case, 1942; 61156 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Harry Bridges letter to Citizens Committee and VGM, 1942-1983; 61155 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Lawyers Guild to President of the U.S. requesting cancellation of Harry Bridges deportation, 1945; 61154 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between VGM and Harry and Nikki Bridges, includes newspaper clippings, 1985-1986; 61153 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Journalism Career, 61084
  Series IV: Journalism Career, consists of five chronologically arranged subseries that represent the different newspapers and the various cities in which she lived and worked, and which primarily contain copies of Gardner's articles, and correspondence. The subseries and employment/residence dates are: A. Chicago Tribune(1930-1941); B. Federated Press (Washington D.C., 1942-1943); C. New Masses(Washington D.C., 1943-1947); D. Los Angeles (1947-1952), Peoples World; E. New York (1952-1980s), Daily Worker and after.
  - Subseries IV:A: Chicago Tribune, 61128
    - Chicago Tribune Newspaper articles by VG, 1930-1937; 61150 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Misc. correspondence and research materials while at the Chicago Tribune, 1937-1940; 61149 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Tribune correspondence, 1937-1940; 61148 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Photocopy of 12/25/38 Picture Section of Chicago Tribune includes a picture OF VG, 1938; 61147 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Don Max, possibly Tribune related, 1939; 61146 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Tribune manuscript, undated; 61145 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy Chicago Sunday Tribune cover page, 1938; 61144 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Tribune stories by VG, undated; 61142 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence regarding Tribune firing, undated; 61140 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Settlement of VG's Tribune case, 1940; 61139 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Tribune articles by VG, 1930-1938; 61138 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Tribune Documents, undated; 61137 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Photocopies of photoprints "Signing of Hearst Chain Peace Formula" ending Chicago strike., 1940; 61136 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence:Guild activities at The Tribune, 1937; 61135 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Copies of the Tribunit, Guild newspaper of the Chicago Tribune workers, 1938-1939; 61134 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Newspaper Guild of New York and Chicago, 1941; 61133 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - St. Louis Newspaper Guild Newsletter, undated; 61132 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Union Songs by Chicago Newspaper Guild, undated; 61131 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Guild activities and songs., undated; 61130 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Eulogy for Morgan Hull of Los Angeles Newspaper Guild, undated; 61129 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Subseries IV:B: Federated Press, Washington D.C., 61121
    - Political hassles at Federated Press, 1942-1943; 61127 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Federated Press articles by VG, 1942-1943; 61126 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Federated Press articles by VG, 1943; 61125 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Letter of resignation, 1943; 61124 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence and Union Leader, 1943; 61123 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Job related, 1942-1943; 61122 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Subseries IV:C: New Masses, Washington D.C., 61118
    - New Masses:Articles by VG, 1944-1947; 61120 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - New Masses: Articles by VG, 1944-1947; 61119 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Subseries IV:D: California employment, 61104
    - Peoples Voice; New Masses:Articles by VG, 1946-1947; 61117 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Challenge Newspaper: Articles by VG, 1947; 61116 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Regarding Councilman Davenport's anti- communist attack and Los Angeles Fire and Police article, 1948; 61115 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Peoples World speech in San Francisco fundraising effort, 1948; 61114 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence:Masses and Mainstream, 1949; 61113 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper article by VG in Daily Peoples World, 1950; 61112 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Newspaper article by VG in Daily Peoples World on Terminal Island, in Our World newspaper, 1951; 61111 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Daily Peoples World: Correspondence, 1950-1952; 61110 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Peoples World:Articles by VG and correspondence, 1951; 61109 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - VG's case from California Review Committee, regarding Peoples World employment, 1951-1956; 61108 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - On getting fired by Slim, correspondence etc. from Peoples World employment, 1951; 61107 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Political notes to self on Slim Meeting, undated; 61106 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Peoples World staff meeting speech by VG, undated; 61105 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Subseries IV:E: New York employment, 61085